자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)
좋아요, 한 번 더요
All right, one more.
자, 한 번 더. 절 보세요
One more, look at me and uh...
크게 웃어요. 아, 좋아요, 좋아
Big smiles. Ah, that's perfect.
네, 좋습니다
Yes, okay.
자, 이제 단체 사진을 찍을 테니
Um, we're gonna get a group shot.
절 따라오시죠
So I need you guys to come in with me.
아, 신부 들러리들과 신랑 들러리들
여기로 오세요. 어서요
Uh, I need the bridesmaids
and the best men, please.
좋아요
All right.
실례합니다
Excuse me.
늦었군
You're late.
가지고 있나?
Do you have it?
모두 다?
All of it?
좋아
Good.
하던 대로 하는 거지?
Shall we do this in the usual way?
그래, 그러지
Yeah, yeah.
호텔 온천탕이 좋을 것 같군
Hotel spa will be fine.
5분 뒤야
그래, 5분 뒤에
Five minutes.
Yeah, five minutes.
뭐야?
What?
아니, 이건...
No, this isn't...
대체 뭔 수작인 거야?
What the hell
do you think you're doing?
날 엿 먹일 수 있다고 생각해?
You think you can screw with me?
협상 가격이 방금 올랐어
My price just went up.
만 달러 더 내놔야 해
It's gonna cost you another 10 grand.
안 그러면 FBI에 전화해서
딱 20초만 통화하도록 하지
Or I could just make one
20-second phone call to the FBI.
혹시 FBI 전화번호 알아?
You wouldn't happen
to know their number, would you?
아니, 됐어
You know, that's all right.
그냥 전화국에 번호 물어볼게
그게 훨씬 쉬운 일...
I'll just call information.
It'll be a lot easier to...
여보세...
Hel...
여보세요?
Hello?
개자식...
Son of a bitch.
어디 있는 거지?
Where are you?
MONK Season 4 Epi. 7
Mr. Monk Goes to a Wedding
토니 샬롭
(에이드리안 몽크 役)
트레일러 하워드
(나탈리 티거 役)
제이슨 그레이 스탠포드
(랜달 디셔 경위 役)
테드 리바인
(리랜드 스토틀마이어 경감 役)
딕테이션
김철균(kim1047@nate.com)
싱크편집
윤선영(seedyun@nate.com)
한글번역
이재연(vostoc@nate.com)
번역수정
김철균(kim1047@nate.com)
한글교정
이미란(lmr0412@nate.com)
ORIGINAL AIR DATE ON USA: 2005/08/19
- 놀랬죠 / 놀랬지!
- 짜잔!
- Surprise. / Surprise!
- Surprise!
생일 축하하네, 디셔
Happy birthday, buddy.
감사합니다. 감사합니다
Thank you. Thank you.
노래 시작...
For...
♪ 당신은 재밌고 멋진 친구예요 ♪
♪ for he's a jolly good fellow ♪
He's a jolly good fellow
for he's a jolly good fellow
- ♪ 정말 재밌고 멋져요 ♪
- 아주 근사해요
- For he's a jolly good fellow...
- This is great.
정말 멋져요! 저는...
This is awesome! I mean...
여러분이 기억해주실 줄 몰랐어요
I can't believe you remembered.
물론 기억하고말고
어떻게 잊어버리겠나?
Of course we remembered.
How could we forget?
- 저희 엄마가 전화하셨죠, 그렇죠?
- 지난달 내내 그러셨지
- My mom called you, didn't she?
- Every day for the past month.
- 이건 뭐예요?
- 셀로판지야
- What's that?
- It's cellophane.
- 몽크의 생각이지
- 케이크를 보호하기 위한 거야
- Monk's idea.
- It's to protect the cake.
- 더 재미있게 하려는 거지
- 어떻게요?
- Makes it more fun.
- For what?
그러니까 자네가 촛불을 불어서 끌 때
항상 그 뭔가가...
Well, when you blow out the candles,
there's always a little...
내가 침이라고 부르는...
what I call spittle...
이건 정말 좋은 생각이지
생일 케이크용 침 보호막이라고
Actually a pretty good idea.
It's a birthday cake spittle shield.
이건 내가 정말 투자하고 싶단
생각이 든 최초의 몽크 아이디어일세
You know, that's the first idea
that you've had that I might actually
consider investing in.
- 감사합니다
- 소원을 빌어요
- Thank you.
- Make a wish.
촛불 끄게, 경위
Blow out the candles, lieutenant.
생일 축하해
Hey, happy birthday.
투자 문제는 재고해봐야겠군
I think I might reconsider that investment.
괜찮아요
It's okay.
괜찮아요. 아뇨, 아뇨, 괜찮다니까요!
It's okay. No, no, it's okay!
전 생일 케이크를 원한 게 아니라...
I don't need a birthday cake...
바로 이 방에 있는 여러분에게
사랑받는다는 느낌을 원했던 거니까요
To feel the love I'm feeling
in this room right now from everybody.
여보세요 / 제가 필라델피아의
템플 대학에 다닐 때였죠...
Hey. / It wasn't long ago I was a senior
at Temple university in Philadelphia...
뭐라고요?
What?
안 돼요, 로저. 안 돼요
No, Roger, you can't.
왜냐하면, 안 되니까요
Because you can't.
그러니까 다른 사람이 없단 말이에요
Well, I can't find anybody else.
그 저녁식사는 오늘이라고요, 로저
결혼식은 내일이고요
Because the dinner's tonight, Roger.
The wedding's tomorrow.
의사가 뭐라는데요?
So what did the doctor say?
그럼 진짜로 파열된 건 아니잖아요
So it didn't technically burst.
알겠어요. 좋아요, 로저
몸 관리나 잘해요
All right, fine, Roger,
you take care of yourself.
끊어요
Bye.
대체 맹장이 하는 게 뭐예요?
그건 쓸데없이 딸린 것일 뿐이잖아요!
What does an appendix do, anyway?
I mean, it's an appendix!
즉, 없어도 된단 거죠, 그렇죠?
That means it's extra, right?
내가 해 줄 일은 없어요?
Is there anything I can do?
물론 내가 불편하지 않을 일로 말이에요
That wouldn't inconvenience me?
있어요
Yes.
나랑 같이 내일 내 동생 결혼식에 가요
You can come with me tomorrow
to my brother's wedding.
- 내 짝이 방금 못 오겠대요
- 결혼식이요? 안 돼요, 어...
- My date just canceled.
- A wedding? No, uh...
미안해요. 나탈리, 안 되겠어요
I'm sorry. Natalie, I can't.
그건 안 좋은 생각으로
이유가 일곱 가지는 있다고요
It's a bad idea for
for, for seven reasons.
아니다, 여덟 가지...
아니, 이제 아홉 가지예요
Wait, eight, actually,
now that I think of nine.
아홉 가지 이유로요
난 안 돼요. 못 가요
Nine reasons.
I'm, I can't.
음, 전 그날 휴가예요
만약에 다른 사람을 못 찾으면요
Well, I've got the day off.
I mean, if you can't find anybody else.
경감님, 그린버그 씨 말이에요
아직도 그 보호 감찰관이랑 데이트해요?
Hey, is Greenburg still
dating that parole officer?
아니, 결혼했는데
No. He married her.
사실, 전 턱시도도 갖고 있지요
Actually, I own my own tuxedo.
아! 그럼 저번 주에 잡아들인
무단침입 용의자는요?
Ooh! What about that B&E suspect
you brought in last week?
- 꽤 귀엽게 보이던데요
- 보석금 내줄 만큼 귀엽진 않을걸요
- He was kinda cute.
- Not cute enough to make bail.
당신이 우리 가족을 만난다고 하면
전 흔쾌히 승낙할 텐데요
I'd be honored if you met my family.
- 이건 데이트가 아니에요
- 알아요
- It's not a date.
- I understand.
전.. 전.. 그냥 방패가 필요한 거예요
혼자서 가족들을 만나긴 힘들거든요
I just, I, I need a buffer.
I can't handle my family alone.
네, 전 방패예요
전 완충 역할을 잘해요
I'm a buffer.
I mean, I'm very buff.
말장난 아니라고요
I mean, no pun intended.
물론 웃겨보려는 생각이었지만요
Of course, I thought
I was being funny.
- 따로 방 쓰는 거예요
- 아, 그럼요
- Separate rooms.
- Oh, I should think so.
좋아요, 고마워요
All right, thank you.
여기 초대장이 있어요
장소는 페블 비치예요 / 좋군요
Here is the invitation.
It's in Pebble beach. / Cool.
- 조나단 데븐포트가 누구죠?
- 제 동생이에요
- Who's Jonathan Davenport?
- That's my brother.
'데븐포트로 항상 키스하고 싶어지는
상쾌한 너'에 나오는 치약 이름과 비슷하군요
You're always kissably fresh
with Davenport, like the toothpaste.
사실 비슷한 게 아니에요
I'm actually not like the toothpaste.
그 치약 이름 맞아요
We are the toothpaste.
뭐라고요?
What?
설마요
Get outta here.
잠깐만요 / 뭔데요?
Wait a minute. / What?
이거라고요? / 네
This is you? / Yeah.
왜 그동안 말 안 했어요?
Why didn't you ever tell us?
몽크 씨, 3분 동안만 우리 가족과
있어보시면 이해하실 거예요
Mr. Monk, if you spent three minutes
with them, you'd understand.
그런 이유로 미치의 성을 쓰는 거예요
우리 가족의 어떤 부분도 원하지 않아요
I kept Mitch's name for a reason.
I don't want any part of them or that.
- 그럼 당신은 돈이 아주 많다는 거죠?
- 내가 아니라 가족들이죠
- So I guess you're kinda loaded, huh?
- They are.
가족들은 나에게 땡전 한 푼 안 줄 거고
준다 해도 제가 안 받을 거예요
They wouldn't offer me a nickel.
I wouldn't take it if they did.
이 일로 절 보는
시각이 바뀌는 건 아니죠?
This doesn't change anything, does it?
당연하죠 / 그럼요, 왜 그러겠어요?
No. / Well, why would it?
당신은 여전히 나탈리이고
당신은 여전히 당신이죠
You're, you're still Natalie.
You're, you're still you.
- 그리고 우린 여전히 우리고요
- 그리고 당신은 부자고요
- And we're still us.
- And you're loaded.
네, 데븐포트 가가 그렇죠
Yeah, Davenport.
카렌!
Karen!
네, 데븐포트 부인?
Yes, Mrs. Davenport?
망할 사진사 어디 있나?
Where the hell is the photographer?
나보고 여기서 보자고 하더니만
He told me he would meet me here.
모르겠는데요
I don't know.
- 하지만, 계속 찾아볼게요
- 고마워
- But I will find him for you.
- Thank you.
잠깐
Hey.
이게 다 뭐니?
What are these?
- 아, 칵테일 냅킨인데요
- 칵테일 냅킨은 사각형이어야지
- Uh, they're cocktail napkins.
- Cocktail napkins are square.
나, 난 이게 뭔지 모르겠구나
I, I don't know what that is.
- 네, 지금 바로 고칠게요
- 부탁해
- Okay, I'm gonna fix this right away.
- Please.
카렌
Karen.
이 사람 누구니?
What is he?
어, 웨이터인데요
Uh, he's a waiter.
아니, 그러니까 미국인이냐는 말이지?
히피나 뭐 그런 쪽 아냐?
No, I mean, is he native American?
Is he a hippie? What?
오, 전 잘 모르겠는데요
Oh, I, I don't know.
음, 이 사람 내일 웨이터 일
하지 못하게 했으면 한다
Well, I just don't think
he should serve tomorrow.
별로 격에 맞는 사람이 아냐
I mean, he just doesn't quite fit.
아, 그리고 라타투유 스튜를 준비하자는
생각이 바뀌었어. 뚝뚝 떨어질 거야!
Oh, and I've change my mind
about the ratatouille. It'll drip!
여기저기 국물이 뚝뚝 떨어질 거라고
요리사에게 말해 둬!
It'll drip all over everything.
Tell the cook!
내가 이 모든 걸
다 해야 한단 게 믿어져요?
Do you believe I have to do everything?
그래요
Yes, dear.
아가야!
Princess!
아버지세요?
Is that your dad?
로버트 데븐포트세요
모두 바비라고 부르죠
Robert Davenport.
Everybody calls him Bobby.
- 할아버지!
- 어디 보자! 오!
- Grandpa!
- Look at you! Oh, god!
넌 세상에서 제일 예쁜
들러리 소녀가 되겠구나
You're gonna be the prettiest
flower girl in the world.
안녕, 예쁜아
Hello, sweetheart.
- 아버지는 뭐하세요?
- 재산을 상속하시죠
- What does he do?
- He inherits money.
- 그럼 어머니는요?
- 성함은 페기예요
- What about your mom?
- That's Peggy.
두 가지 취미가 있으시죠
She has two hobbies.
하나는 테니스고 또 하나는
절 비참하게 만드는 거죠
Tennis, and making me feel like dirt.
둘 다 아주 잘하세요
She's a champion at both.
- 두 분 다 멋져 보이세요
- 오, 그럼 당신과는 잘 맞겠군요
- They look nice.
- Oh, then you'll fit right in.
멋지게 보이는 건 여기서
중요한 관심사거든요
Because looking nice
is what matters around here.
제가 고등학생 때
두 분의 관심사는 오로지
When I was in high school,
all they cared about
제가 좋은 집안 출신의 좋은 남자애와
데이트하느냐 아니냐 하는 것이었거든요
was whether I was dating
the right guy from the right family.
그래서요? 그랬어요?
And? Did you?
기대에 못 미치는 남자들하고만 데이트했죠
그중 몇 명한테는 아주 실망했고요
I dated all the wrong guys.
Some of them were really wrong.
미치처럼요
Like Mitch.
부모님은 여전히 미치 사진을
피아노 위에 놓길 거부하세요
They still refuse to put
his picture on the piano.
그게 무슨 의미가 있나요?
What, that means something?
네, 그건 부모님과 저에겐
의미가 있는 일이에요
Yeah, it means something
to them, and me.
맙소사, 땀나네요
God, I'm sweating.
저분들에게 알레르기 반응이
나는 것 같아요. 웃기죠?
I feel like I'm allergic to them.
Is that possible?
기다려요. 이리 와요
이리 와요. 와봐요
Wait, come here, come here, come here.
- 암호가 필요해요
- 암호요?
- I need a signal.
- Signal?
그래요. 제가 패닉 상태에 빠지면
몇 시냐고 물을게요
Yeah. If I start to panic,
I'll ask you what time it is.
그럼 절 데리고 나가주시면 돼요, 아시겠죠?
그냥 절 끌어내 주시면 돼요
Okay, just get me out of there, all right?
Just drag me away.
"몇 시예요?"라고요. 알겠어요
"What time is it?" I got it.
걱정 마세요
Don't worry.
안녕, 엄마
Bye, mom.
안녕, 아가야
Hello, sweetheart.
안녕, 내 사랑
Hello, my dear.
아, 이쪽은 제 친구예요
랜디 디셔라고 해요
Oh, this is my friend.
This is Randy Disher.
데븐포트 씨, 부인
만나 뵙게 되어 반갑습니다
Mr. and Mrs. Davenport,
it's a pleasure to meet you.
두 분 다요
Both of you.
두 분에 대해 멋진
얘기들을 들었답니다
I've heard great things about you.
이를 테면요?
Like what?
어, 그게, 그러니까 정확히는
두 분에 관한 건 아니고
Well, uh, I mean, not about you,
specifically.
치약에 관한 거 말이에요
About your toothpaste.
특히 입 냄새 제거 향까지
포함한 새 치약은 정말 좋았어요
Especially that new kind with
the mouthwash built right in.
두 분이 그런 착상을 하신 게
틀림없는 거 같군요
Bet you were the inspiration for that.
왜요? 나한테서
입 냄새가 나나요?
Why? What's wrong with my breath?
몇 시예요?
What time is it?
네?
What?
- 몇 시냐고요?
- 이게 아닌데요
What time is it? / No...
이 블러드 메리 칵테일 맛이
좀 이상한 것 같아요. 아, 아가야!
There's something wrong
with this bloody Mary. Oh, honey!
네가 바텐더잖니. 맛 좀 보려무나
You're a bartender. Taste that.
엄마, 전 이제 바텐더가 아니에요
Mom, I'm not a bartender anymore.
아, 그래. 미안하구나
넌, 그 뭐냐...
Oh, I'm, I'm sorry.
You're, you're, um,
신참 형사라고 했나?
a junior detective or something.
전 사립 탐정의 조수예요
I'm an assistant to a private investigator.
한가지 일 좀 진득하게 하렴
이번이 17번째 바꾼 거지?
It's just so hard to keep straight.
I mean, what is this, job number 17?
랜디, 멋진 친구. 부탁인데
이거 맛 좀 봐줘요
Randy, sweetheart, be a dear.
Taste this for me.
뭐가 잘못된 거죠?
What's wrong with it?
- 셀러리 소금이 덜 들어갔네요
- 아, 바로 그거예요
- Not enough celery salt.
- Oh, that's it.
그게 내가 생각하던 거였어요
That's exactly what I thought.
좋아요. 조나단은 어디 있어요?
아직 테레사도 못 봤는데요
Okay, so where's Jonathan?
I haven't even met Theresa yet.
오, 너도 그 애를 사랑하게 될 거다
정말 환상적인 아이야!
Oh, you're going to love her.
She's fantastic!
아니 잠깐만요
정말로 허락하셨군요
Hold the presses.
You actually approve.
그럼, 그럼. 허락했고말고
Well, yes, we approve.
허락 안 했으면 우리가
여기에 서 있겠니?
We'd hardly be standing here
if we didn't approve.
- 그럼 그 여자 조사 좀 해보셨겠네요
- 그래, 내가 했지
- So I guess you had her checked out.
- Yes, I did.
이 모든 게 아주 빠르게 진행됐단다
This all happened very quickly.
걔들은 3주 전에 하와이에서
만났다는구나
Yeah, they met about
three weeks ago in Hawaii.
테레사는 결혼한 적이 없고
양친이 모두 돌아가셨는데
She's never been married.
Both of her parents are deceased.
탄탄한 신탁 펀드에
의존해 살아왔더구나
She's been living off
a very healthy trust fund.
큰 액수지 / 그러니 테레사가
돈 보고 온 건 아니지
Huge. / So this girl
is not after the money.
정말 사랑하는 거야
This is the real thing.
조나단은 아주 행복해 한단다
Jonathan's very happy.
테레사가 조나단을 행복하게 해준다니
그거면 다 된 거잖니
She makes him happy.
That's all that matters.
미치도 절 행복하게 해줬어요, 엄마
Mitch made me happy, mother.
냇. 페그
Nat. Peg.
이건 절대로...
This is never gonna...
오늘은 조나단의 날이야
논쟁은 피하는 게 어떨까?
This is Jonathan's day.
Can we not do this?
좋아요. 안 그러죠
줄리 찾으러 가 볼게요
Okay. I won't.
I'm gonna go find Julie.
음, 저흰 아직 체크인 안 했거든요
Well, we haven't checked in yet.
중앙 사무실이 어디에 있죠?
Which way is the main office?
계단 내려가서 뒤쪽으로
주차장을 지나면 있다네 / 좋군요
Back down the steps
and across the parking lot. / Great.
나중에 봬요, 페기. 바비
See you later, Peggy. Bobby.
이보게, 난 가봐야겠네
Hey, listen, I gotta get going.
- 자네 괜찮지, 응?
- 네, 괜찮아요
- You're okay, right?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
절 보살펴줄 필요는 없다고요
You don't have to check in on me.
아니, 그래야하네
Yes, I do.
나탈리한테 약속했거든
I promised Natalie that I would.
엄마의 두 눈을 걸고 맹세했어
And I swore on my mother's eyes.
반장님, 전 아기가 아니에요
Captain, I'm not a baby.
여기 있으면 전 괜찮을 거예요
I'll be fine here.
혼자서요
Alone.
하루종일, 여기서요
All day. Here.
뭐 좀 마실 거 있나?
You got something to drink?
냉장고에 있어요
It's in the fridge.
문 안쪽에 목록 적힌 게 있는데
색깔별로 구분되어 있어요
There's a chart on the inside of the door.
It's color-coded.
난 목록 필요 없네, 몽크
I don't need the chart, Monk.
난 나탈리와 랜디가 어떻게
하고 있을지 궁금하네만
Hey, I wonder how Natalie
and Randy are doing.
난 결혼식이 좋다네
I love weddings.
자네 나하고 카렌이 결혼식장에서
만났단 거 알고 있지?
Did you know that I met
Karen at a wedding?
어쨌든 난 결혼식이 좋다네
I love weddings anyway.
자네 심정 이해해
Yep.
자네 누가 근사한 결혼식을
치렀었는지 아나?
You know who had a great wedding?
바로 자네야. 자네하고 트루디
You did. You and Trudy.
정말 대단한 날이었지
Now, that was a great day.
사진첩 어디에 있나?
Where is that photo album?
트루디는...
She was...
와! / 아름다웠지
Wow! / Beautiful.
전 결혼식이 진행되는 동안 트루디가
꽤 심하게 울었던 게 기억이 나요
I remember during the service
she was crying so hard,
"네"라는 말도 못할 정도였죠
she couldn't even say the words, "I do."
그렇게 울던 사람 또 본 적 있으세요?
Have you ever seen anybody
cry so much?
운 건 자네였어, 몽크
That was you, Monk.
자네 말고 그리 울던 사람을
본 적이 없네
And, no, I have not.
랜디, 랜디. 운전사가
누구였는지 봤나?
Randy, Randy, son, did you see
who was driving the car?
봤어? 운전자를
식별할 수 있겠어?
Did you see?
Can you I.D. the driver?
봤어요
I saw that.
- 은색의 볼보였어요
- 아냐, 아냐. 랜디. 차는 여기 있어
- Silver Volvo.
- No, no, Randy, we got the car.
차는 여기 있으니 됐고
누가 운전했느냐고?
It's right here.
Who was driving?
반장님... / 응?
Captain... / Yeah?
전 번호판을 봤어요
I got a license plate.
번호판 필요 없다니까, 랜디
바로 지금 보고 있다네
I don't need the license plate, Randy.
I'm looking right at it.
4, 폴의 "P"...
찰스의 "C"...
Four, Paul...
"C," Charles...
- 괜찮아지겠죠, 네?
- 네, 진통제 놓을게요
- He's gonna be okay, right?
- Yeah, painkillers.
랜디는 좀 어때요?
How's he doing?
팔이 부러졌고 다리도 부러졌소
아마 갈비뼈 두어 대도 나갔을게요
Broken arm, broken leg.
Probably a couple of broken ribs.
여행 가방이 충격을 받아냈기에 망정이지
안 그랬으면 더 안 좋을 뻔했소
Suitcase took most of the blow.
It could have been a lot worse.
- 운전자를 식별할 수 있겠대요?
- 나도 식별 못 할 거요
- Can he identify the driver?
- He can't identify me.
나중에 다시 시도해봐야죠
뭐 알아냈나?
He'll try again later.
What do you got?
수증기가 응축된 걸로 봐서
에어컨이 작동 중이었어요
Condensation.
The air conditioner was running.
현재 습도가 약 70% 정도니까
And the humidity is, what?
About 70%.
저 차는 여기서 약 20분간
공회전하고 있었던 거예요
So that car was idling right here
for about 20 minutes.
그러니 뭐 이 작자가 여기서
랜디를 기다리고 있었다고?
So, what, he was waiting for him?
여기 타이어 자국을 보건대
From the tire tracks here,
최고 속도까지 갑자기 가속했을 겁니다
he must have peeled out full speed.
브레이크를 밟으려고조차 안 했단 거네
So, what, he didn't even try to brake.
혹은 방향을 틀려고도 안 했단 거고
Or make the turn.
개자식!
Son of a bitch!
무슨 일이 있었던 겁니까?
What happened?
여기 겨우 한 시간밖에 안 있었는데
그새 누군가를 열 받게 한 거요? / 아뇨
He was only here for an hour.
Did he piss somebody off? / No.
또 차 바닥에서 이걸 발견했어요
And we found this
on the floor of the car.
가속 페달 근처에서요
녹색 진흙 종류 같아요
Near the gas pedal.
Some kind of green mud.
음, 바로 실험실로 보내도록 하지
Well, I'll get that to the lab right away.
- 반장님, 이건 반장님 사건이 아녜요
- 아니라니 웃기지 말아요
- Captain, it's not your case.
- Like hell it's not.
저분 말이 맞아요, 반장님
여긴 우리 관할이에요
She's right, captain.
It's my backyard.
몬테리 카운티 경찰서의
브리스토 경감입니다
Lieutenant Bristo.
Monterey county police.
안녕하시오?
How you doing?
걱정 마세요. 보고서의
사본을 다 보내드리리다
Don't worry, you'll be
copied on every statement.
어디 머무시오?
Where you staying?
어, 아마 여기 있을 거 같군요
Uh, right here, I guess.
이쪽은 에이드리안 몽크인데
역시 여기에 머물 거요
This is Adrian Monk.
He'll be staying here too.
- 저.. 전 그럴 생각이 없는데요
- 이 사람도 여기에 있을 겁니다
- I, I, I don't think so.
- He'll be staying here too.
네, 저도 여기에 있을게요
I guess I'll be staying here too.
음, 저 차량은 마가렛 데븐포트
앞으로 등록되어 있군요
Well, the car's registered
to a Margaret Davenport.
마가렛 데븐포트라고요?
Margaret Davenport?
마지 고모!
Aunt Madge!
아, 그분이 고모님이시군요
Okay, aunt Madge.
고모는 누군가
코트 보관 방에 걸어둔
She said somebody took the keys
out of her coat pocket,
코트 주머니에서
차 열쇠를 빼간 거라시더군요
which was in a cloak room.
고모는 장식하느라 바쁘셨고요
She was busy putting up decorations.
그럼 고모는 범인이 아니군요
So it wasn't her.
하지만, 범인은 어딜 뒤져야 할지
정확히 알고 있었고요
But he knew exactly where to look.
그런데 어떤 차가 고모님 차인지 알았죠?
And what car was hers?
열쇠에는 볼보 마크도 없었는데요
There's no Volvo markings on that key.
누구든지 가능해요
고용인이라든가 어...
That could have been anybody.
An employee, uh...
그건 아닐 겁니다
I don't think so.
I just talked to the manager.
방금 관리인과 얘기해 봤는데
직원회의 중이었답니다
There was a staff meeting in progress.
전부 참석했었데요
Nobody was missing.
뭐예요? 그럼 우리 가족 중 누군가
이 일을 저지른 거라고요?
What? You're saying somebody
in my family did this?
아니에요
No.
위층으로 올라가 보지 않겠나?
Why don't we get you upstairs?
호텔 측에서 무료로 객실을 제공해줬다네
Hotel's comping you a room.
얘야
Honey.
- 곧 따라갈게요
- 알겠수다
- I'll catch up with you guys later.
- Okey-dokey.
- 아, 그래. 친구는 좀 어떠니?
- 괜찮길 바라야죠
- Oh, yes, how is he?
- I hope he's gonnabe all right.
아, 그래. 예쁜아
친구가 저리돼서 유감이구나
Oh, now, sweetheart,
I'm sorry about your friend.
하지만, 네가 할 수 있는 일은 없단다
But there isn't anything that you can do.
그러니 우리는 지금...
So now we just have to...
뭔데?
what?
- 역경에 굴하지 말고 하던 일 해야죠
- 맞아. 하던 일 계속 해야지
- We soldier on.
- That's right. We soldier on.
저녁식사 예행연습이
20분 뒤에 시작될 거야. 그러니...
Uh, now, the rehearsal dinner
is in about 20 minutes, so...
이거 뭐예요?
What's that?
아, 이거 밖에서 발견했는데
Uh, oh, I found this outside.
그거 랜디 바지 조각이에요
But those are Randy's pants.
아. 그러니? 난 웨딩 플래너에게
식탁보 색을 결정하게
Oh, yes, I thought that
this color would be good to show
보여줄 샘플로
가지고 있던 거란다
the wedding planner for the tablecloths.
- 카키색요?
- 아니, 피 말이야! 진홍색!
- Khaki?
- No, the blood! Crimson!
웨딩 플래너가 준비해 온 식탁보는
짙은 자주색이었는데
The ones she picked
were sort of raspberry.
어떤 꽃과도 안 어울렸어
Didn't go with any of the flowers at all.
엄마, 그건 증거물 봉투예요
Mom, that's an evidence bag.
나도 안다 / 범죄 현장에서
이걸 빼내 오시면 안 돼요
Yes. / You can't just take it
from a crime scene.
그건 중죄라고요
That's a felony.
죄라면 테이블보가 죄지, 아가야
Well, the tablecloths are a felony, darling.
- 그리고 난 이걸 돌려줄 거야
- 엄마, 이거 가지고 계시면 안 돼요
- And I'm going to give it back.
- Mom, you can't just keep it.
난... 안 돼!
I, no!
나탈리 제인!
Natalie Jane!
고맙다, 아가야
Thank you, darling.
자, 저녁식사 예행연습이
20분 후쯤에 시작될 테니
Now, the rehearsal dinner's
going to be in about 20 minutes.
그 옷 입고 오면 안 된다, 알겠지?
So you're not gonna be
wearing that, are you?
몽크 씨! / 나탈리, 호텔 가게에서
내 칫솔을 팔지 않는대요
Mr. Monk! / Natalie, that gift shop
does not have my toothbrush.
거틀러 4000을 가져다 놓지 않는대요
나 어떻게 하죠?
They do not carry the Gertler 4000.
What am I supposed to do?
그건 나중에 걱정하기로 해요
We're gonna worry about that later.
서둘러요. 우리 늦었다고요
Come on, we're late.
The rehearsal dinner's in 20 minutes.
저녁식사 예행연습이
20분 후에 시작한다고요
"우리"라고 했어요?
You said "we"?
"우리 늦었어요"라고 했어요?
"우리"라고 한 거 맞죠?
You said "we're late?"
I heard you say "we."
- 몽크 씨가 제 파트너예요. 축하드려요
- 아, 잠깐만요!
- You're my date. Congratulations.
- Oh, wait!
- 문제가 있어요
- 몽크 씨, 누군가가 랜디를 해쳤어요
- Here's the thing.
- Mr. Monk, someone did this to Randy.
아마 우리 가족 중의 한 사람이요
Maybe somebody in my family.
당신은 탐정이잖아요, 안 그래요?
이건 탐색해볼 절호의 기회라고요
You're a detective, right?
This is your chance to look around.
- 문제가 있어요
- 문제가 있다고요?
- Here's the thing.
- Here's the thing!
난 절대로 저기 혼자 안 가요!
당신이 내 파트너예요!
I can't go in there alone!
You're my date!
실례합니다
Excuse me.
제가 남들 앞에 일어서서
연설하는 경우가 거의 없는데
Oh, I don't normally stand up
and give speeches.
이제 곧, 그 이유를
아시게 될 겁니다!
In a minute, you're gonna find out why!
그리고 약속드리건대
내일 이후로는
And I promise, after tomorrow,
말하는 건 거의 다
조나단한테 부탁할 거예요
I'm gonna let Jonathan
do most of the talking.
너무 믿지는 마세요
Don't bet on it.
음, 여기 계신 여러분께 절
편하게 대해주셔서 감사하고 싶어요
Um, I just wanted to thank you, all of you,
for making me feel so at home.
저도 이 모든 게 빠르게 진행된 건 알아요
I know this all happened very quickly.
전 아직도 여러분이 일주일 사이에
이 모든 걸 어떻게 준비하셨는지 모르겠어요
I still don't know how you
planned all this in one week.
몇 분은 아시겠지만
제 부모님은 1995년에 돌아가셨죠
As some of you know,
I lost my own parents in 1995,
전 이런 가족적 분위기를
다시 느낄 수 있을 거라 생각 못했어요
and I never thought I would
ever feel this way again.
그래서...
So...
데븐포트 씨, 부인
Mr. and Mrs. Davenport,
우리가 어제 만났을 때 제게
엄마, 아빠라 부르라고 하셨죠
when we met yesterday, you asked me
to call you mom and dad.
그땐 정말 뭐라고 말해야 할지
미처 몰랐지만 계속 그 생각을 했답니다
At the time I didn't really
know what to say,
but I've been thinking about it,
and mom and dad...
엄마, 아빠...
기꺼이 그렇게 부를게요
I would love to.
나탈리, 제가 필라델피아에서 자라면서
언니가 있었으면 했었죠
Natalie, when I was growing up
in Philadelphia,
I used to dream about having a big sister.
어서 빨리 언니랑
친해졌으면 좋겠어요
I can't wait to get to know you better.
오늘 밤에 조촐한
독신 파티가 있을 텐데
I'm having a little
bachelorette party tonight.
- 언니가 꼭 와주셨으면 해요
- 오, 그러죠!
- I really hope you can make it.
- Oh, yeah!
그만 해요!
Stop it!
이 사람이 계속 내 음식에 손대요!
He keeps touching my food!
아뇨, 안 그랬어요
No, I wasn't.
전 이 애를 도와주려던 거였어요
I was just helping the lad.
애가 뭔가에 혼란스러워 보였거든요
He seems kind of confused about...
여기 있는 것들을
전부 뒤섞어 놓잖아요
It's mushing all together here.
얘는, 음, 얘는 괜찮아요
좋아질 겁니다
He's, uh, he's fine.
He's gonna be all right.
배경이 좋군요
You have a nice background here.
아주 좋아요. 고마워요
Very good. Thank you very much.
반장님, 뭐하고 계세요?
Captain, what are you doing?
사진 찍고 있어요
Taking pictures.
어머님께서 사진사가 보이질 않는다고
말씀하시던 걸 우연히 들었죠
I overheard your mother say that
the wedding photographer didn't
show up, so I volunteered.
그래서 제가 나선 거예요
이건 현장 감식반원에게서
빌린 거고요 / 왜요?
I borrowed this from
one of the crime tech guys. / Why?
왜냐고? 그야 랜디가 범인을
식별할 수 있을 거라고 말했으니까
Why? Because Randy says that he thinks
he might be able to identify the driver.
- 제대로 봤다던가요?
- 그럼
- Did he get a good look at him?
- Yep.
백인 남성이고 중간 정도의 키에
빨간 야구 모자와 선글라스를 썼대
Male caucasian, medium build,
red baseball cap, sunglasses.
사진 몇 장 찍어서
오늘 밤에 현상할 생각이야
I figured I'd take some pictures,
get them developed tonight.
혹시 운이 따라줄지도 모르잖아
And maybe we'll get lucky.
잠깐만요. 제 동생 결혼식에서 비밀
수사 중이신 거예요? / 그렇소
Wait. You're undercover at
my brother's wedding? / Yeah.
봐요, 난 호의를 베풀고 있는 거요
Look, I'm doing you a favor.
이런 식으로 은밀히 할까요 아니면
다 위층으로 끌고 가서 한 사람씩 찍을까요
It's either this, or we take
everybody upstairs, one at a time.
웃어요
Smile.
아주 좋아요
Very nice.
- 안녕, 누나. 몽크 씨
- 안녕, 동생아!
- Hey, sis. Mr. Monk.
- Hey, bro!
그거 잘 어울려 보이는데?
That looks good on you.
- 아, 옷 말이야?
- 아니, 미소
- Oh, the suit?
- No, the smile.
얘는 절대 웃지 않았죠
He never smiles.
웃을 일이 없었던 거지
Never had anything to smile about.
충고 하나 해드려요?
당장 나가서 딴 사람 찾아요
You want my advice?
Get out now, save yourself.
천만에요, 충고는 고맙지만
전 아무 데도 안 갈 거예요
No. No, thanks.
I'm not going anywhere.
죽음이 우릴 갈라놓을 때까지요
Till death do us part.
아, 근데 친구 분은 좀 어떠세요?
디셔 경사님 말이에요
Hey, how's your friend?
Sergeant Disher.
아, 디셔 경위예요
Oh, it's lieutenant Disher.
좀 심하게 다쳤지만
괜찮아질 거예요
He got pretty banged up.
But he's gonna be okay.
바로 이 건물 밖에서 그런 일이
생겼다니 믿을 수 없어요
I can't believe that
happened right outside.
그러게요. 꽃이라도 좀 보내고 싶어요
Yeah, we wanted to send him
some flowers.
- 어느 병원에 계세요?
- 아, 여기로 다시 돌아왔어요
- Which hospital is he in?
- No, he's back here.
위층에서 그냥 쉬고 있죠
He's upstairs. Just resting.
아, 잘됐네요!
Oh, good!
직접 꽃을 전해드리면 되겠군요
Well, we can deliver the flowers ourselves.
그렇네 / 그분이 내일 결혼식에
참석하실 수 있을 것 같아요?
Yeah. / Do you think he'll be able to
make it to the wedding tomorrow?
오, 안됐지만 아마 안 될 거예요
Oh, gosh, probably not.
- 정말 유감이네요
- 아, 저기 말이에요
- That's too bad.
- Oh, you know what?
저의 새 시아버님께 마실 것 좀
갖다 드리러 가야겠어요
I think I'm gonna bring
my new father-in-law a drink.
아, 언니, 잊지 말아요
파티는 304호예요
Oh, hey, don't forget,
in room 304, party.
그럼...
So...
내가 이런 말을
하게 될지는 몰랐지만...
I can't believe I'm
about to say this but...
엄마 말씀이 맞아. 정말 멋지구나
테레사가 아까운걸?
Mom was right. She's great.
You don't deserve her.
맞아
I don't.
우리에겐 87가지 공통점이 있어
We have 87 things in common.
어젯밤에 실제로 목록을 만들어 봤지
Last night, we actually made a list.
- 알았어. 그만 해
- 미친 짓이지
- Okay, stop it.
- It's crazy.
그럼 전혀 가족이 없다는 거예요?
동생이나 언니, 오빠도?
And she doesn't have any family at all?
Brothers, sisters?
없어요. 삼촌이 한 분 계셨는데
No, she had an uncle,
그녀 부모님과 함께 마드리드로
향하는 팬암기에 타고 계셨대요
but he was on that Pan Am
flight to Madrid with her parents.
팬암기였대요?
It was a Pan Am flight?
네. 정말 끔찍한 일을 겪어왔어요
Yeah. God, she's been through so much.
하지만, 그게 테레사를 강하게 만들어줬죠
But it's made her stronger.
그리고 그게 전해졌는지
저도 강해지는 것 같아요
And it's rubbing off.
I feel stronger too.
- 곧 나도 누나처럼 강해질 거야
- 오, 그래
- Soon I'll be strong like you.
- Oh, right.
아마 테레사가 날 찾고 있을 테니
가봐야겠어요
She's probably looking for me,
so I'm gonna go.
그리고 내일 봐
But I'll see you tomorrow.
많이 마셔
Gulp.
왜요?
What?
아무것도 아녜요
Nothing.
뭔데요?
What is it?
아까 테레사가 자기 부모님이
1995년에 돌아가셨다고 했는데
Well, she, she said her parents
died in 1995.
팬암 항공사는 91년에 문 닫았어요
Pan Am went out of business in '91.
그래요? 아마 약간 뭔가를 혼동했겠죠
So? She got a little mixed up.
그랬겠죠
Yeah.
사용 중지
Out of Service
이런, "M"이 엉망이네
No, that M is a disaster.
이 사람은?
이 사람은 음, 이 사람은...
How about this guy?
That's, uh, that's
멤피스에서 오신 퍼디 삼촌이래
uncle Ferdy from Memphis.
아녜요 / 아니야?
No. / No?
네
No.
- 나탈리 사촌이래
- 아녜요
- That's Natalie's cousin.
- No.
테레사 사진은 없어요?
No pictures of Theresa?
신부? 물론 있지. 어...
The bride. Sure. Uh...
이게 뒷모습이 찍힌 거야
This is the back of her head.
그것 참 이상하군. 제대로 신부를
찍은 게 없네
That's weird. I don't have
a good shot of her.
이봐, 혹시 범인이 여자였던 거 아냐?
Hey, could it have been a woman?
네, 그럴 수도 있죠
Yeah, I guess so.
자넨 테레사가 범인일지도
모른다는 거야? / 글쎄요
- You think maybe she's the guy?
- I don't know.
- 부모님에 대해 거짓말을 했거든요
- 우리가 확인해 볼게
- She did lie about her parents.
- We'll check her out.
제가 받을게요
I'll get it.
이젠 더 큰 수정액 병이
필요하겠네
All right, I'm gonna need
a bigger bottle.
어, 랜디 디셔 방인데요
스토틀마이어입니다
Uh, Randy Disher's room.
This is Stottlemeyer.
뭐라고요?
What?
네. 압니다
Yeah. I understand.
금방 거기로 내려가죠
Uh, we'll be down there in a minute.
- 시체를 발견했대
- 어디서요?
- They found a body.
- Where?
온천이래
In the spa.
- 누군데요?
- 모르지
- Who is it?
- No idea.
자, 가자고
Okay. Let's go.
자넨 아무 데도 가면 안 돼
You're not going anywhere.
밑에서 만나세
나탈리를 찾아 와
Look, meet me downstairs.
Find Natalie.
여기 숙녀 분들에게 사소한
불평 신고가 들어왔네요
We had a few complaints
about you ladies.
수갑 가져오기를 잘했죠
It's good thing I brought my handcuffs.
음, 경찰관님. 전 나쁜 소녀였어요
Um, officer, I've been a bad girl.
여보세요. 여보세요
Hello, hello.
실례합니다
Excuse me.
이봐요. 나탈리
Hello. Natalie.
나탈리
Natalie.
실례합니다
Excuse me.
나탈리
Natalie.
몽크 씨, 무슨 일이에요?
랜디 씨는 괜찮아요?
Mr. Monk. What's going on?
Is Randy okay?
뭐 잘못됐나요?
Anything wrong?
어, 네. 지금 엄마랑
얘기 좀 하러 가야 할 것 같네요
Oh, uh, yeah. I just need
to go talk to my mom.
다시 올 테니 파티 계속 해요
Uh, I'll be back. Party on.
잘 놀아요!
Bye!
아, 이봐요. 당신도 오면 좋겠네요
Oh. Hey, you better come too.
저요?
Me?
아래층에 시체가 있거든요
There's a body downstairs.
187 사건(살인사건)처럼 보여요
Looks like a 187.
187 사건요? / 네, 브리스토
경감님이 거기에 계신데
A 187? / Yeah. Lieutenant Bristo's
down there,
제 생각에 당신이 내려오길
바라실 거 같아서요
and I think he wants you down there too.
가시죠 / 네
Let's go. / Okay.
이쪽으로요
This way.
갑니다
I'm coming.
그.. 그건 뭐예요?
What, what's that?
제 휴대용 스테레오인데요
My boom box.
휴대용 스테레오요?
Boom box.
아, 그래요. 가기나 합시다
Okay. Fine. Let's just go.
운동 좀 하신 것 같군요
You look like you work out a little bit.
노력하고 있죠
I try.
전 필라테스 운동 기구를
알아보고 있답니다
I'm looking into pilates.
왔나, 몽크
Hey, monk.
이 사람은 누구예요?
Who is he?
아직까지는 신원 미상입니다
So far, he's John Doe.
이 사람 지갑이 아직도 진흙
목욕탕 속에 있다는 걸 알아냈죠
We figure his wallet's
still in the mud bath.
이 진흙이 저 밖에서 일어난 사고 때
자네가 차 안에서 발견한
I'm willing to bet
that that mud is the same mud
진흙과 같다고 장담할 수 있지
that you found outside in the car.
- 이자가 운전자라고요?
- 아뇨, 그렇진 않아요
- Was he the driver?
- No. Not likely.
검시관에 따르면 피해자가 죽은 건
적어도 36시간 전이라고 합니다
According to the coroner,
this guy died at least 36 hours ago.
반장님, 이자는 결혼식 사진사예요
그 사라졌다던 사진사 말이에요
Captain, he's the wedding photographer.
The one that's been missing.
그걸 어떻게 아나요?
How do you know that?
이 사람 손가락에 얼룩이 있거든요
The discoloration on his fingertips.
현상액 때문에 생긴 것이죠
It's caused by developer fluid.
다른 사진사들에게서도 이런 걸 봤어요
I've seen it on other photographers.
몽크 씨가 같이 계셔서 기쁘군요
Glad he's on our team.
몽크 씨 말이 맞고
이 사람이 여기 사는 사람이라면
Well, if you're right and he's local,
아마 시내에 저 사람 사진관이 있을 겁니다
he'll probably have a studio in town.
수색 영장을 얻을 수 있을 거예요
We'll get a search warrant.
저 사람 여기서 뭐 하는 거죠?
What's he doing here?
오, 혼도 씨예요. 저랑 같이 왔죠
Oh, that's Hondo. He's with me.
여기 사람들을 좀 통제해야
할 것 같아서 오라고 했죠
Figure we might need
a little crowd control.
잠깐 얘기 좀 할래요?
Can I talk to you for a sec?
몽크 씨, 저 사람은
진짜 경찰이 아니에요
Mr. Monk, he's not a real cop.
스트립퍼라고요
He's a stripper.
설마요
I don't think so.
저 사람 배지 못 봤어요?
Didn't you see his badge?
It said, "officer feel good."
거기에 "경찰관이 기분을
풀어드립니다"라고 쓰여 있잖아요
그럼...
So...
몽크, 저 사람 벨트에 꽂혀있는
지폐들 안 보이나?
Monk, the guy's got dollar bills
sticking out of his belt.
지갑을 잃어버린줄 알았어요
I thought he lost his wallet.
1초만 기다려봐요
Hold on a sec.
이제 1분만 기다려봐요
Now wait a minute.
이런, 내 신발 위에
떨어졌어요, 나탈리
Oh, it's on my shoe.
Natalie.
아, 싫어. 싫어!
Ah, no, no!
물티슈...
Wipe.
물티슈!
Wipe!
아니, 더 큰 게 필요해요!
No, I need something bigger!
저 사람에 대한
당신 말이 맞는 것 같군요
You may be right about him.
미안해요. 알렌 판사님이 오리 사냥하러
멀리 떠나 있으셨어요
Sorry. Judge Allen was
upstate duck hunting.
여기 있어요. 수색 영장이요
You got it. Search warrant.
우린 정당하게 허가받은 겁니다
We are duly authorized.
아주 예뻐 보이는구나
You look so pretty.
아빠가 널 자랑스러워하실 거야
Your daddy would be so proud of you.
친애하는 친구 분들
Beloved friends,
우리는 오늘 여기 테레사와 조나단의
결혼을 축하해주기 위해 모였습니다
we're gathered here today to celebrate
the union of Theresa and Jonathan.
이 둘은 만난 지 겨우 3주 됐지만
Two met just three weeks ago.
둘 사이엔
진정한 사랑이 싹텄습니다
But true love has found between.
사진사 이름은 프랭크 러들이었소
The guy's name was Frank Ruddle.
은행 계좌를 살짝 조사해 보았는데
I got a peek at his bank account.
파산했더군요
He was broke.
하루 벌어 하루 먹고살았더군요
Living paycheck to paycheck.
이런 얘기도 들었죠
Get this.
여동생이 그러는데 프랭크가
부동산 업자들과 만났다더군요
According to his sister, he'd been
talking to real estate agents.
집 보러 다니러요
Looking at houses.
어디선가 돈 들어올 데가
있다고 생각했나 봐요
Thought he was gonna come into
some money.
이게 웬 떡이야
Hello.
알아냈어요. 알아냈다고요
I got it. I got it.
그리고 신부 테레사 스콧은 조나단
데븐포트를 기쁠 때나 슬플 때나
And do you, Theresa Scott,
take Jonathan Davenport
to love, honor, and cherish
부유할 때나 가난할 때나
아플 때나 건강할 때나
for better or worse,
richer or poorer,
죽음이 갈라놓을 때까지
사랑하고 존경하고 아끼겠습니까?
in sickness and in health
until death do you part?
네
I do.
캘리포니아 주 정부에서
제게 준 권한으로
By the power vested in me
by the state of California,
두 사람이 남편과 아내가
되었음을 선언합니다
I now pronounce you husband and wife.
신부에게 키스하세요
You may kiss the bride.
조나단 데븐포트 부부를 소개합니다
May I present you Mr. and Mrs.
Jonathan Davenport?
오, 맙소사
저 여자군요. 테레사요
Oh, my god.
It's her. It's Theresa.
저 여자는 블랙 위도우야
(남편을 죽이고 돈을 가로채는 여자)
She's a black widow.
이건 테레사가 아니야
It's, it's not her.
머리가 다르잖아 / 엄마
금발로 물들이고 자르기만 하면 돼요
Her hair is different. / Mom, she
dyed her hair blond and cut it.
테레사가 아니야
It's not her.
오늘은 조나단 생에 가장 행복한 날이다
네 동생에게 뭐 하는 짓이니?
This is the happiest day of his life.
Why are you doing this to your brother?
조나단을 위해서 이러는 거예요
엄마, 이걸로 다 설명이 되잖아요
I'm doing this for Jonathan.
Mom, this explains everything.
왜 가족이 없는지
왜 친구가 없는지 말이에요
Why she has no family,
why she has no friends.
가장 친한 친구는 아프고 부모님은
돌아가셨기 때문이잖니
Because her best friend is sick
and her parents happen to be dead.
이 기사 읽어 보셨잖아요?
Did you read this article?
유산을 노리고 첫 남편을 죽였다잖아요
She killed her first husband for his money.
- 또 저지르려고 한 게 틀림없어요
- 아냐, 아니야
- She might be planning to do it again.
- No, no.
아냐. 아냐. 아냐. 접어 둬라
난 못 믿겠다
No, no, no. Cancel, cancel.
I don't believe it.
데븐포트 부인, 랜디 디셔는 6년 전에
그 사건 수사를 담당하는 경찰이었습니다
Mrs. Davenport, Randy Disher was
the investigating officer 6 years ago.
테레사를 알아볼 수 있었죠
He could identify Theresa.
그래서 랜디가 여기 오자마자
차로 친 겁니다
That's why she tried to
run him down when he first got here.
죄송하지만 그건 정말
터무니없는 소리군요
I'm sorry.
But that is simply preposterous.
- 뭔가 느껴져!
- 야아!
I feel something!
Hey!
어제 테레사는 디셔 경사님이라고 호칭했죠
Yesterday, she called him sergeant Disher.
테레사가 6년 전에 디셔를
알고 있을 땐 경사였으니까요
He was a sergeant
when she knew him 6 years ago.
실례하네만, 젊은이
자리 좀 비켜 주겠나. 고맙네
Excuse me, young man,
could you just go. Thank you.
너나 나나 이게 뭐에 관한 건지
알고 있잖니
We both know what this is about.
테레사에 관한 것도 아니고
This is not about Theresa and
누군가 발견한 그 멍청한 사진사에
관한 것도 아니야
some stupid photograph that
somebody found.
이건 너와 나에 관한 거야
This is about you and me.
- 오, 엄마. 제발 그만 하세요
- 아무렴, 너랑 나랑 미치에 관한 거지
- Oh, mom, please stop.
- Yes. Yes. You and me and Mitch.
내가 미치를 부당하게 대했다는
네 생각 때문이지
And the fact that you think
that I treated him badly,
오, 이건... / 또 내가 미치 사진을
피아노 위에 안 놓았기 때문이지
Oh, this is... / And I never put
his picture on the piano
거기엔 아무 의미도 없는데 말이야
as if that meant anything.
난 정말 네가 어떻게
저런 남자 밑에서 일하는지
I really don't see
how you can work with that man
or how you can take
anything he says seriously.
어떻게 저런 남자가 말하는 것 따위를
진지하게 받아들이는지 모르겠다
실례해도 될까요?
May I?
예, 물론이죠
Yes, of course.
절 모욕하시는 건 아니죠?
Should I be insulted?
뭣 때문에요?
About what?
냅킨요
The napkins.
절 만지는 게 두려우세요, 몽크 씨?
You afraid to touch me, Mr. Monk?
제가 왜 당신을 무서워하겠어요?
Why would I be afraid of you?
당신과 결혼한 것도 아닌데요
I'm not marrying you.
드레스가 아름답군요
It's a beautiful dress.
오, 고마워요
Oh, thank you.
게다가 여전히 잘 맞는군요
And it still fits.
무슨 뜻이에요?
What do you mean?
6년 전에 필라델피아에서
똑같은 드레스를 입었잖아요
You wore the same dress
in Philadelphia 6 years ago.
그땐 달린 콜리지라는 이름을 썼었죠
At the time, you were using
the name Darlene Coolidge.
프랭크 러들이 찍은
그때 결혼사진 중 하나를 봤어요
I saw the wedding pictures,
the ones that Frank Ruddle took.
누구요?
Who?
프랭크 러들요
Frank Ruddle.
치명적인 실수를
저지른 결혼식 사진사 알죠?
The wedding photographer who made
the fatal mistake of recognizing you.
당신을 알아본 거 말이에요
몽크 씨, 전...
Mr. Monk, I'm not...
당신이 생각하는 사람이 아니에요
who or what you think I am.
확실히 전 아니라고요
I am denying it unequivocally.
하지만, 당신 말이 맞다고 해도
However, if you were right,
또 제가 그런 여자라고 해도
and I was such a woman,
절 절대 막으실 수는 없을걸요
the last thing you'd wanna do
is get in my way.
지금 협박하는 거요?
Are you threatening me?
안녕
Hi.
어떻게 할 계획이죠?
How do you plan to do it?
조나단을 어떻게 죽일 거예요?
How are you going to kill him?
노래가 끝났네요, 몽크 씨
The song's over, Mr. Monk.
실례합니다, 데븐포트 부인
Excuse me, Mrs. Davenport.
이건 우리 주제곡이잖아
They're playing our song.
오, 이리 와!
Oh, come here!
자기가 그리웠어
I missed you.
테레사 방에 무단 침입했어요?
그거 불법 아니에요?
You broke into her room?
Is that legal?
체크아웃한 호텔 방에 들어갈 때는
수색 영장이 없어도 돼요
You don't need a search warrant to go into
a hotel room if it's after checkout.
그거 정말이에요?
Is that true?
- 나도 몰라
- 뭘 가져왔나요?
- I don't know.
- What you got?
빨간 야구모자
Red baseball cap.
짜잔 / 녹색 진흙이군요
Ta-da. / Green mud.
- 좋아요, 저 여자를 체포하러 가죠
- 안 돼요, 안 돼요, 안 돼!
- All right, let's arrest her.
- No, no, no!
나탈리! 나탈리!
Natalie! Natalie!
- 이 증거로 테레사를 엮을 순 없어요
- 하지만, 뭔가 해야 해요
- We can't get her on this.
- But we have to do something.
신혼여행지가 멕시코인데다
몇 분 안에 떠날 거라고요
They're honeymooning in Mexico.
They're gonna leave any minute.
랜디가 테레사를 달린 콜리지라고
증언해주면 우리가 잡을 수 있죠
If Randy can id her as Darlene Coolidge,
then we've got her.
내가 랜디를 일으킬 수 있는지
가서 보고 오지
I'm gonna go see
if I can wake him up.
저 여자 여기에 잡아둬요
Keep her here.
절대 테레사가 떠나게 하지 말게
Don't let her leave.
시간이 됐어
It's time.
그래
Okay.
누나, 우리 이제 가보려고
Hey, we're heading out.
벌써? / 응
Already? / Yeah.
테레사가 좀 더 이른
비행기를 타고 싶대
Theresa wants to catch an earlier flight.
테레사가 뭔가 결정하면
그걸로 끝이야
When she makes up her mind
about something, that's it.
- 여자는 거부할 수 없는 힘이잖아
- 가지 마
- The woman's a force of nature.
- Don't go.
너랑 얘기할 게 있어
I, I need to talk to you.
나 없어도 재밌잖아
나 없이도 잘 놀았으면서
Oh, you don't need me to have fun.
You never did.
안녕하세요. 이이 좀 데려갈게요
Hi. I've got to take him.
- 데려가도 괜찮죠?
- 행운을 빌어줘
- I've got to take him, okay?
- Wish me luck.
조나단
Jonathan.
Theresa.
테레사
몇 마디 드릴 말씀이 있습니다
Just wanted to say a few words.
전...
I...
전 사실 저 신혼부부에 대해서
그렇게 잘 알지는 못합니다
well, the truth is I don't really know
either of you very well.
하지만, 전 결혼 생활에 대해
몇 가지를 알고 있죠
But I do know a couple of things
about marriage.
제 아내 트루디가 늘 말하기를...
My wife Trudy used to say...
결혼은 90%의 사랑과
that marriage is 90% love
10%의 용서로 이루어진다고 했습니다
and 10% forgiveness.
트루디가 저와 결혼한 걸로 봐서
용서에 관한 한 전문가로 볼 수 있죠
She was married to me,
so she was sort of an expert
in forgiveness.
이건 실제 이야기입니다
That's a true story.
- 이런 제기랄!
- 그건 내버려둬요
- Son of a bitch!
- Forget it.
- 자물쇠라도 채웠어?
- 관두세요. 전 괜찮아요
- Is there a latch?
- Forget it, I'm good.
- 괜찮다고?
- 그래요, 가요!
- You're good?
- I'm good, go!
괜찮으니 가세요
어서 가시라고요!
Okay. / Go, let's go.
어서 와!
Come on!
어서, 어서, 어서 와!
Come on, come on, come on!
어쨌든 여러분 모두가 이 자리에
참석해주셔서 정말 감사 드립니다
Anyway, I, I'd like to thank
all of you for coming.
그리고 바비 씨와 페기 부인을
대변하는 듯하군요
And I think I speak
on behalf of Bobby and Peggy.
아뇨, 천만에요
우릴 대변하는 게 아니에요
No, uh, no, actually, you're not.
당신들...
You...
음, 조나단과 어, 테레사
저, 전...
And, um, Jonathan and, and Theresa,
I, I, uh...
전 당신들이 잠시 틈을 내서
I, I know you want
to take a, a minute now
멋진 웨이터와 웨이트리스들에게
감사의 말씀을 전하고 싶다는 거 압니다
and just say thank you to
our wonderful waiters and waitresses.
맞아요. 물론이요
Yes, absolutely.
좋아. 좋아
Great, great.
이제 여기에 줄리 티거 양이
나올 겁니다
You know who's here, though,
is, uh, Julie Teeger.
어서 올라와 주세요, 줄리 양
Come up here, Julie.
어서 올라오세요
Come on up here, please.
모두 아시겠지만
줄리는 조나단의 조카이지요
Julie, you know, is, uh,
of course, Jonathan's niece.
어서, 어서 올라와요
Come, come, come on.
줄리 양은 학교에서
시를 하나 배웠는데
She has, uh, had to, uh,
memorize a poem for, for school.
조나단과 테레사를 축하하며
여러분 앞에서 그 시를 암송하겠답니다
And she would like to recite it for you now
in honor of Jonathan and Theresa.
줄리 티거 양입니다
Julie Teeger.
- 어서 오렴, 줄리. 어서 오렴
- 좋아요, 안녕
- Come on Julie, come on girl.
- Okay, bye.
루이스 캐롤의 윌리엄 신부님
Father William by Lewis Carroll.
"당신은 늙으셨어요, 윌리엄 신부님"
하고 젊은이가 말했습니다
"You're old, Father William,"
the young man said.
"신부님 머리카락이
아주 백발이 되어버렸군요
"And your hair has become very white."
미안해요
Sorry.
"그런데도 여전히 신부님은
야릇한 행동을 하시네요"
"And yet you incessantly
stand on your head."
"신부님 연세에 그러한 행동이
어울린다고 생각하시나요?"
"Do you think, at your age,
this is right?"
"신부님 연세에 그러한 행동이
어울린다고 생각하시나요?"
"Do you think, at your age,
this is right?"
- 언제나 저를 사로잡는 구절이죠
- 그래, 좋아, 좋아!
- That always gets me.
- Okay, okay, okay!
아이쿠!
Shoot!
제가 젊었을 때에는...
When I was just a lad...
우린 가봐야겠다
잘했어. 잘했어
We're gonna go.
Good job, good job.
아, 젊은이가 아니었군요
좀 더 어린...
Well, not a lad.
You know, more of a young...
녀석일 때요
fella.
청년 때요
You know, adolescent.
사실은 십대 때요
A teenager, really.
자, 가요
Okay, fine.
기다려!
Hang on!
안녕, 달린
Hey, Darlene.
오랜만이군
Long time, no see.
이 여자가 맞나?
Is this her?
달린 콜리지예요
Darlene Coolidge.
2001년에 시애틀에서
쫓다가 놓쳐버렸죠
We lost track of you
back in Seattle in 2001.
그때는 저 여자 이름이
필리스 제프니였어요
But by then, her name
was Phyllis Gaffney,
이미 세 번째 남편과
살고 있었죠
and she was already
on husband number three.
그 남자는 5주 반밖에 더 못 살았어요
He lasted five and a half weeks.
그만큼 살려두다니
그 남자를 아주 사랑했었나 봐
You really must've loved him.
이 사람이 뭐라고 하는 거니?
What's he talking about?
진정해. 진정해
멍청한 짓 하지 말라고
Okay, okay,
don't do anything stupid.
어서 나가야 한다고 말했잖아
Told you we should've eloped.
이봐요! 아빠...
Hey! Dad...
- 개인 제트기 갖고 있죠?
- 회사 소유라네
- You have a private jet.
- It's a company jet.
연료 채워서 20분 안에
출발할 수 있게 준비해줘요
I want it fueled and ready
to go in 20 minutes.
우리 가족에게서 떨어져
Stay away from our family.
우린 이미 문제가 많거든
We have enough problems.
고마워요
Thank you.
자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)